Finding Aid for Bay City (Mich.) city government records, 1898-1933
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Bay City (Mich.) city government records 1898-1933
Bay City (Mich.)
1 linear foot
8576 Cc.5 2
Records of the municipal government offices of Bay City, Michigan. Correspondence files of the mayor, city attorney, the city manager, and the city engineer.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were the gift of Mrs. Paul Baker (donor no. 4044 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
Catherine Baker, the donor of these records, was a historian of the people and businesses of Bay City, Michigan. These Bay City government files, slated for destruction, were retrieved and donated to the Michigan Historical Collections.
The Bay City, Michigan city government collection consists of the records of various city offices dating between 1898 and 1933. Included are files of the mayor, city attorney, the city manager, and the city engineer. Prior to 1905, the records were of East and West Bay City, separate municipal entities which merged in that year to form Bay City. Most of the papers are from the mayor's office. Robert V. Mundy served as the city's mayor from 1907 to 1915 and again from 1917 to 1921. Mundy's term of office was interrupted by Frank P.S. Kelton who served one term as mayor from 1915 to 1917. In 1921 John Dean was elected mayor. Topics in the files include the city's water supply, life on the home-front during World War I, the League to Enforce Peace, veterans' affairs, the city's campaign against venereal disease in 1920, unemployment, and the work of the Michigan Municipal League.
Subjects:
League to Enforce Peace.; Municipal government--Michigan--Bay City.; Public health--Michigan--Bay City.; Unemployed--Michigan--Bay City.; Sexually transmitted diseases--Michigan--Bay City.; Veterans--Michigan--Bay City.; Water-supply--Michigan--Bay City.; World War, 1914-1918.
- Mayor's and City Attorney's File
  - 1906-1908 (Box 1)
  - 1908 (Box 1)
  - 1909, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - 1910 (Box 1)
  - 1911 (Box 1)
  - 1912 (Box 1)
  - 1913, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - 1914, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1915, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1916 (Box 1)
  - 1917, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - 1918, 10 folders (Box 1)
  - 1919, 9 folders (Box 1)
  - 1920, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1921, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - 1922 (Box 1)
  - 1923 (Box 1)
  - 1924 (Box 1)
- City Manager's File
  - 1931 (Box 1)
  - 1932 (Box 1)
  - 1933, 2 folders (Box 1)
- City Engineer's File
  - 1898 (Box 1)
  - 1899 (Box 1)
  - 1901 (Box 1)
  - 1902, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1903 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Fire Department, 1927-1929 (Box 1)
  - Applications (sample) for City Manager, 1920-1921 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 1)